<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects | Tim White</title>
    <link>https://timwhite0.github.io/project/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://timwhite0.github.io/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Projects</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://timwhite0.github.io/media/icon_hudd9b251b05fa576c42ec1aa19b8230a1_38775_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://timwhite0.github.io/project/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forecasting the weather with deep learning</title>
      <link>https://timwhite0.github.io/project/stats604weather/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://timwhite0.github.io/project/stats604weather/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Did machine learning reveal symbolism, emotionality, and imaginativeness as primary predictors of creativity?</title>
      <link>https://timwhite0.github.io/project/stats604creativity/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://timwhite0.github.io/project/stats604creativity/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analyzing mortality and its determinants among individuals with type 1 and type 2 diabetes</title>
      <link>https://timwhite0.github.io/project/stats601project/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://timwhite0.github.io/project/stats601project/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Diabetes mellitus has consistently ranked among the ten leading causes of death in the United States for the past several decades. Diabetes-related mortality is prevalent across a wide range of sociodemographic subpopulations, and many previous studies have attempted to identify the risk factors and comorbidities that contribute most heavily to this phenomenon. However, surprisingly little attention has been paid to the distinction between the type 1 and type 2 variants of the disease in the context of mortality. In this report, we fill this gap in the literature by using unsupervised and supervised statistical learning methods to analyze the mortality risk profiles of individuals with type 1 and type 2 diabetes. We apply a dimension reduction technique to multiple-cause-of-death mortality data from the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention to explore the latent sociodemographic and health profiles of individuals whose deaths were attributed to diabetes in 2021, and we train several classification models to differentiate between type 1 and type 2 diabetes as a cause of death based on these characteristics. Our results suggest that sophisticated classification methods are capable of achieving moderate accuracy in distinguishing deaths due to type 1 diabetes from those due to type 2 diabetes, with tree-based and optimization-based classifiers such as random forest, AdaBoost, and kernel SVM providing a better holistic performance than model-based classifiers such as naive Bayes, quadratic discriminant analysis, and penalized logistic regression. We find that age is the most useful predictor for this classification task, followed by other sociodemographic predictors such as education, marital status, race, place of death, and sex. These findings provide important insights that could potentially improve the ability of practitioners to assess mortality risk in patients with type 1 and type 2 diabetes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MLBdash</title>
      <link>https://timwhite0.github.io/project/mlbdash/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://timwhite0.github.io/project/mlbdash/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twhit.shinyapps.io/MLBdash/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;MLBdash&lt;/a&gt; is an R Shiny dashboard with projected standings and team statistics dating back to 1998.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The first tab lists each team&amp;rsquo;s projected wins and losses, which are the average of the projections from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.baseball-reference.com/leagues/majors/2022-playoff-odds.shtml&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Baseball Reference&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.baseballprospectus.com/standings/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Baseball Prospectus&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The second tab contains a plot of OPS+ (offensive performance) versus ERA+ (pitching performance) and assigns teams to tiers by partitioning the coordinate space of this plot.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The third tab presents the information from the first two tabs for every season since 1998, which was the first season in which the MLB expanded to 30 teams.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MLBdash will be updated for the 2024 season in April of 2024.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A resampling technique for massive data in settings of bootstrap inconsistency</title>
      <link>https://timwhite0.github.io/project/umn_honors_thesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://timwhite0.github.io/project/umn_honors_thesis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As massive data sets become more and more prevalent across the sciences, there is a growing need for accurate and computationally efficient methods of estimator quality assessment that can be applied under a variety of data-generating conditions. The nonparametric bootstrap is a straightforward and accurate method for approximating the sampling distribution of an estimator, but it becomes computationally unwieldy for large samples. Kleiner et al.’s bag of little bootstraps (BLB) provides a computationally efficient alternative to the bootstrap, but it is not expected to perform well in settings where the bootstrap is inconsistent. In this paper, we introduce the bag of little m out of n bootstraps (BLmnB), a modification of the BLB that aims to extend the method’s applicability to cases of bootstrap inconsistency. We formalize the BLmnB algorithm and compare its performance against that of the bootstrap and the BLB in two well-documented settings of bootstrap failure. Our results indicate that while the BLmnB is capable of outperforming the other two methods in one of these settings, it performs no better than the BLB in the other. In both settings, we find that the approximation accuracy of the BLmnB is sensitive to the choice of the resample size m. While these findings suggest that the BLmnB is a promising alternative to the BLB in at least some data- generating scenarios, further investigation is necessary in order to develop the underlying theory of the method and study its accuracy and runtime in other settings of bootstrap inconsistency.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
